Inventaris van de Raffles-Minto Manuscript Collection, 1810-1814
Nationaal Archief, Den Haag
Collectie 215 Raffles
Raffles-Minto
1810-1814
C22106
0.40 meter; 4 inventarisnummers.
Nationaal Archief, Den Haag
Raffles, Thomas Stamford (1781-1826)
Elliot-Murray-Kynynmound, Gilbert (Lord Minto) (1751-1814)
Het archief bestaat uit kopieën van brieven van de Britse gouverneur-generaal van Indië, Thomas Stamford Raffles, aan zijn voorganger Lord Minto. De brieven zijn geschreven in de periode 1810-1813 vanuit onder meer Malacca (Singapore), Batavia, Buitenzorg en Samarang.
Archiefvorming
Geschiedenis van het archiefbeheer
Early in 1969 it was learned that forty-eight volumes of the first Earl of Minto's papers, containing original letters and other documents by and concerning Sir Thomas Stamford Raffles, were being offered for sale abroad by a private vendor in London. The price being asked for these manuscripts was £15,000, and their owner was the well-known London surgeon, Mr. A Dickson-Wright. Dr. John Bastin, Reader in the Modern History of South East Asia at the School of Oriental and African Studies, was keenly interested in the matter, and he approached the vendor and secured his agreement to the price being reduced to £10,000 if it were guaranteed that the manuscripts, once purchased, would be kept in safe custody in a public institution in this country. The Blue Funnel Line was asked to assist in raising funds to purchase the manuscripts. This they did, themselves, making a substantial contribution. The manuscripts were then presented to the India Office Library, where the bulk of the documentary sources relating to Raffles are deposited, and where they are available to scholars from any country who might wish to study them.
De kopieen werden in 1970 verkregen. Zie:
De rechtstitel is (nog) onbekend
2.21
Aanwijzingen voor de gebruiker
Openbaarheidsbeperkingen
Volledig openbaar.
Materiële beperkingen
Aanvraaginstructie
Openbare archiefstukken kunnen online worden aangevraagd en gereserveerd. U kunt dit ook via de terminals in de studiezaal van het Nationaal Archief doen. Om te kunnen reserveren dient u de volgende stappen te volgen:
U maakt een profiel aan op www.gahetna.nl, en logt vervolgens in
Via de archiefinventaris (alleen de beschrijvingen met rode nummers) selecteert u het gewenste archiefstuk door op de knop 'Reserveren' te klikken
In het volgende scherm geeft u aan op welke dag u het archiefstuk wilt inzien
Indien u zich bevindt in de studiezaal en een tafelnummer heeft ontvangen kunt u dit nummer vermelden. Als u geen tafelnummer heeft kunt u tafelnummer 777 laten staan
Vervolgens bevestigt u uw reservering door deze te versturen.
Verwant materiaal
Beschikbaarheid van kopieën
Beschrijving van de series en archiefbestanddelen
- (VOLUME 1), Letters from Thomas Stamford Raffles to Lord Minto.; 1
  - Page 1, Contents: 9th August, 1810
  - Page 6, Contents: Calcutta, 11th July, 1810
  - Page 12, Contents: Prince of Wales Island, 25th November, 1810
  - Page 24, Contents: Prince of Wales Island, 25th November, 1810
  - Page 33, Contents: Malacca, 15th December, 1810
  - Page 53, Contents: Malacca, 24th January, 1811
  - Page 56, Contents: Malacca, 24th January, 1811
  - Page 66, Contents: Malacca, 21st December, 1810
  - Page 70, Contents: Malacca, 4th February, 1811
  - Page 73, Contents: Malacca, 6th February, 1811
  - Page 75, Contents: Malacca, 6th February, 1811
  - Page 101, Contents: Malacca, 6th February, 1811
  - Page 108, Contents: Malacca, 8th February, 1811
  - Page 112, Contents: Malacca, 10th February, 1811
  - Page 114, Contents: Malacca, 18th February, 1811
  - Page 125, Contents: Malacca, 23rd February, 1811
  - Page 127, Contents: Malacca, 17th March, 1811
  - Page 130, Contents: Malacca, 13th April, 1811
  - Page 138, Contents: Malacca, 30th April, 1811
  - Page 144, Contents: Malacca, 6th May, 1811
- (VOLUME II), Letters from Thomas Stamford Raffles to Lord Minto.; 2
  - Page 1, Contents: Batavia, 18th September, 1811
  - Page 5, Contents: Batavia, 19th September, 1811
  - Page 8, Contents: Batavia, 19th September, 1811
  - Page 12, Contents: Batavia, 27th October, 1811
  - Page 13, Contents: Buitenzorg, 28th October, 1811
  - Page 20, Contents: Ryswick, 14th January, 1812
  - Page 23, Contents: Ryswick, 15th January, 1812
  - Page 68, Contents: Batavia, 20th January, 1812
  - Page 69, Contents: Batavia, 24th January, 1812
  - Page 73, Contents: Buitenzorg, 25th January, 1812
  - Page 80, Contents: Buitenzorg, 25th January, 1812
  - Page 97, Contents: Batavia, 27th January, 1812
  - Page 105, Contents: Batavia, 28th January, 1812
  - Page 107, Contents: Batavia, 29th January, 1812
  - Page 108, Contents: Batavia, 29th January, 1812
  - Page 112, Contents: Batavia, 29th January, 1812
  - Page 114, Contents: Batavia, 30th January, 1812
  - Page 118, Contents: Ryswick, 30th January, 1812
  - Page 123, Contents: Buitenzorg, 10th March, 1812
  - Page 129, Contents: Buitenzorg, 15th March, 1812
  - Page 131, Contents: Buitenzorg, 21st March, 1812
  - Page 142, Contents: Buitenzorg, 21st March, 1812
  - Page 144, Contents: Buitenzorg, 21st March, 1812
  - Page 147, Contents: Buitenzorg, 14th April, 1812
  - Page 153, Contents: Ryswick, 17th April, 1812
  - Page 165, Contents: Ryswick, 21st April, 1812
  - Page 172, Contents: Ryswick, 21st April, 1812
  - Page 180, Contents: Batavia, 22nd April, 1812
  - Page 182, Contents: Batavia, 22nd April, 1812
  - Page 188, Contents: Ryswick, 23rd April, 1812
  - Page 193, Contents: Ryswick, 23rd April, 1812
  - Page 212, Contents: Buitenzorg, 27th April, 1812
  - Page 215, Contents: Batavia, 1st May, 1812
  - Page 217, Contents: Batavia, 1st May, 1812
  - Page 219, Contents: Ryswick, 3rd May, 1812
  - Page 223, Contents: Buitenzorg, 12th May, 1812
  - Page 230, Contents: Buitenzorg, 12th May, 1812
  - Page 237, Contents: Chipannus, 22nd May, 1812
  - Page 241, Contents: Cheribon, 27th May, 1812
  - Page 243, Contents: Cheribon, 27th May, 1812
  - Page 250, Contents: Tagal, 28th May, 1812
- (VOLUME III), Letters from Thomas Stamford Raffles to Lord Minto.; 3
  - Page 1, Contents: Samarang, 2nd June, 1812
  - Page 10, Contents: Samarang, 2nd June, 1812
  - Page 16, Contents: Samarang, 5th June, 1812
  - Page 17, Contents: Samarang, 15th June, 1812
  - Page 20, Contents: Samarang, 25th June, 1812
  - Page 28, Contents: Samarang, 3rd July, 1812
  - Page 36, Contents: Samarang, 12th July, 1812
  - Page 41, Contents: Samarang, 14th July, 1812
  - Page 43, Contents: Samarang, 14th July, 1812
  - Page 47, Contents: Samarang, 16th July, 1812
  - Page 52, Contents: Samarang, 6th June, 1812
  - Page 72, Contents: Samarang, 16th July, 1812
  - Page 73, Contents: Samarang, 1st July, 1812
  - Page 75, Contents: Batavia, 16th August, 1812
  - Page 76, Contents: Batavia, 12th August, 1812
  - Page 79, Contents: Salatiga, 5th August, 1812
  - Page 97, Contents: Batavia, 16th August, 1812
  - Page 110, Contents: Samarang, 25th August, 1812
  - Page 113, Contents: Ryswick, 22nd September, 1812
  - Page 125, Contents: Batavia, 22nd September, 1812
  - Page 134, Contents: Ryswick, 10th December, 1812
  - Page 145, Contents: Ryswick, 10th December, 1812
  - Page 167, Contents: Ryswick, 15th December, 1812
  - Page 169, Contents: Batavia, 17th December, 1812
  - Page 171, Contents: Batavia, 6th October, 1812
  - Page 182, Contents: Ryswick, 7th October, 1812
  - Page 184, Contents: Ryswick, 7th October, 1812
  - Page 189, Contents: Ryswick, 7th October, 1812
  - Page 193, Contents: Ryswick, 10th December, 1812
  - Page 212, Contents: Buitenzorg, 12th April, 1813
  - Page 216, Contents: Buitenzorg, 20th April, 1813
  - Page 223, Contents: Buitenzorg, 21st April, 1813
  - Page 237, Contents: Ryswick, 25th April, 1813
  - Page 239, Contents: Ryswick, 25th April, 1813
  - Page 253, Contents: Ryswick, 25th April, 1813
  - Page 256, Contents: Batavia, 28th April, 1813
  - Page 260, Contents: Ryswick, 28th April, 1813
  - Page 264, Contents: Batavia, 28th April, 1813
  - Page 267, Contents: Batavia, 5th May, 1813
  - Page 283, Contents: Buitenzorg, 5th May, 1813
- (VOLUME IV), Letters from Thomas Stamford Raffles to Lord Minto; 4
  - Page 1, Contents: Buitenzorg 18th October, 1813
  - Page 15, Contents: Buitenzorg 13th February, 1814
  - Page 30, Contents: Buitenzorg 13th February, 1814
  - Page 46, Contents: Buitenzorg 13th February, 1814
  - Page 47, Contents: Buitenzorg 14th February, 1814
  - Page 53, Contents: Buitenzorg 5th March, 1814
  - Page 61, Contents: Batavia 18th February, 1814
  - Page 62, Contents: Buitenzorg 21st February, 1814
  - Page 63, Contents: Buitenzorg 11th May, 1814
  - Page 85, Contents: Buitenzorg 1st July, 1814
  - Page 86, Contents: Buitenzorg 2nd July, 1814
  - Page 111, Contents: Ryswick 11th August, 1814
  - Page 119, Contents: Buitenzorg 17th September, 1814
  - Page 121 Contents: Buitenzorg 17th September, 1814
  - Page 140, Contents: Buitenzorg 19th September, 1814
  - Page 143, Contents: Buitenzorg 2nd October, 1814